# ABID HUSSAIN ANJUM

Work Authorization: Visa required except Saudi Arabia

Current Residence: Rivadh Saudi Arabia

Nationality: Pakistani

Mobile No: +966 56 5663825 Email: abid.anjum.sa2019@gmail.com

**DOB**: 15 Feb 1979

Linked In: www.linkedin.com/in/abid-anjum-8371a517b

GitHub: https://github.com/abid-anjum Website: https://abid-anjum.github.io

YouTube: https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCrAqca7Zc2Z7pwNIVK-5bXA

#### **SUMMARY**

16+ years hands on experience in different technologies, design and developed enterprise web and mobile applications, 6 years worked as architect technical lead, ability to work in Parallel on multiple projects in different technologies, worked as full stack web and mobile architect / developer. Being architect design enterprise architecture for Java dotNet and Mobile apps. Good knowledge of designing and development of distributed applications.

**Mobile App Skills** 

Kotlin

Swift

Xamarin

Java Android

Objective C

React Native

Apache Cordova

Good experience working in agile scrum environment.

## **SKILLS**

#### **Java Skills**

- Java
- J2FF
- JSP, Servlets
- EJB
- **Spring Boot Framework**
- **Spring Security**
- JWT Authentication/Oauth2
- Spring Data JPA
- Hibernate
- **Restful Services / Web Services**
- **Micro Services**
- **Dockers and Kubernetes**
- Load balancing with Ribbon
- **Eureka Naming Server**
- RabbitMQ/Kafka
- **Amazon Web Services** experience (EC2, S3, RDS, **Elastic, Cloud Front)**
- JSF, Prime-faces and Oracle **ADF Faces**
- Maven, Gradle
- Git. GitHub
- Jenkins, Linux

### **Databases**

- **PostgreSQL** 
  - My SQL
  - Oracle
  - **SQL** Server
  - MongoDB NoSQL

- Asp.net MVC
- Asp.net Core
- Visual Basic
- LINQ
- **Entity Framework**
- Asp.net Web API
- **Rest/WCF Services**
- **WCF Data Services**
- ADO.net
- SharePoint development in

### **Microsoft Skills**

Asp.net Web form

ORACLE"

DEVELOPER SUITE

- C#

- version 2010, 2013

#### 3+ Years' experience in GIS Area

- **ArcGIS**
- QGIS
- GeoServer
- Leaflet
- Open Layers
- ArcGIS API for JavaScript
- Python Diango and Flask
- PHP and Laravel

#### **Frontend Technologies**

- SPA
- Angular 2+
- React JS
- **Bootstrap**
- HTML 5
- **CSS**
- JavaScript
- Node JS

#### Academic Background

- Master in Computer Sciences yrs. 2004
- Microsoft Certified Professional
- Microsoft Certified Solution developer
- Java Certified Professional

#### **Few Major Projects**

#### 1. SMOS (Smart management operation suit)

Role: As a technical lead

An enterprise web and mobile solution developed in Java, spring Boot, **Angular 8**, Hibernate, Android and IOS platform

#### 2. Logistic operation and support management system

Role: As Lead Developer

A Web and mobile application solution developed in Java, prime faces, EJB, android and IOS platform

#### 3. E-Trading (online trading complete solution)

Role: As Lead Developer

A web application developed in Java, Oracle ADF and EJB

#### 4. Billing system

Role: As Team member

A billing system developed in Java, J2EE, spring boot, Angular2, Hibernate

#### 5. Insurance Management System

Role: As Lead Developer

A web and mobile solution developed in Asp.net MVC, C#, React JS, and mobile app developed in Xamarin Native (android and IOS)

#### 6. ESDIM GIS Mobile App

Role: As a Lead Developer Architect

A GIS mobile application developed in Java android and Swift.

#### 7. Express Mobile App

Role: As a Lead Developer

A mobile application developed in Java android and Swift

#### **Experience**

Organization: (April 2013 - Current)

ANSCL Riyadh Saudi Arabia <a href="https://www.netsoltech.com/">https://www.netsoltech.com/</a>

**Designation:** Lead Full Stack Developer | Architect (Web and Mobile)

#### **Roles & Responsibilities:**

- Understanding client requirements and Programming and develop web and mobile applications
- Produce design document based on requirement study
- Work closely with QA engineers, product managers, UXI experts and designers in order to produce top quality apps
- Work collaboratively with technical team for best technical solutions
- Work as independent and lead a team of developers
- Deploy app on client test and production system and lead UAT activity
- Work closely with product management to communicate trade-offs, alternatives, and effort, and to ensure the very best customer experience
- Take a data driven approach, and pitch in with efforts to innovate to continuously improve delivery speed and quality

Organization: (Jun 2010 to Jan 2013)

NetSol technologies Lahore Pakistan <a href="https://www.netsoltech.com/">https://www.netsoltech.com/</a>

**Designation:** Lead Mobile and web developer/Architect

#### **Roles & Responsibilities:**

- Understand client requirements and Programming and develop web and mobile applications
- Produce design document
- Lead technically develop team
- Close contact with QA department for Quality
- Deploy app on client side and provide training

Organization: (July 2009 to June 2010)

FutureNow technologies Lahore Pakistan www.fnint.com

**<u>Designation</u>**: Senior software developer

#### **Roles & Responsibilities:**

- Write code for new software and maintain existing software code, deployment on client side
- Testing & modification of code, programs, unit testing, bug fixing
- Requirement study & produce design document
- Design user guide, training to client & upgrading of legacy system
- Software technical support to client & problem resolution
- Technical guide to junior team members
- Client communication and training

Organization: (DEC 2007 - JUN 2009)

Eworx International Lahore Pakistan www.eworxintl.com

**Designation:** Senior software developer

#### **Roles & Responsibilities:**

- Write code for new software and maintain existing software code, deployment on client side
- Testing & modification of code, programs, unit testing, bug fixing
- Requirement study & produce design document

Organization: (JAN 2004 - NOV 2007)

Etechsol Lahore Pakistan http://www.etechsol.com/

**Designation:** Software developer

#### **Roles & Responsibilities:**

- Design and develop software according to customer requirement
- Write code for new software and maintain existing software code, deployment on client side
- Testing & modification of code, programs, unit testing, bug fixing